若你要拿來外敷
For external application of urine,
甚麼時候都可以
any time will do.
例如你臨睡前
E.g., before sleep.
當然你不要大汗淋漓的時候去敷
But don't apply it when you're sweating profusely.
你總要把外敷處先洗乾淨And you gotta clean the part for application 1st.
洗乾淨你的面龐
Wash your cheeks clean
然後你才敷啦 如果你頭很髒
before application. If your hair's dirty,
那麼你洗完頭才敷啦
Wash it before application.
這是最基本的了
This is the basics.
你敷完之後 然後你就去看那個酸鹼度
After application, check the alkalinity.
然後你就再慢慢去…
Then gradually...
還有好多好多提議的 我的提議就是
There're many other suggestions. My suggestions
這是我親自做的方法
are based on my own practice.
我覺得我洗完腸之後
I've found that after colonic irrigation,
那個天水和它的酸鹼度是最好的
the alkalinity of the heavenly fluid is the best.
那個天水的味道 各方面的狀態最好
The taste and other aspects of the urine are optimal.
如果你說我那個時候
When my health was very poor,
身體很差的時候呢
as mentioned by you,
我也是混入蒸餾水去飲
I mixed it with distilled water
混了蒸餾水飲 (讓他淡一點)And diluted it.
雖然酸鹼度低了 但它的色素還是很差
Tho' the acidity's lowered, the color's still bad.
氣味還是很大
The odor's still strong.
所以我就知道 不是因為我食了肉
So I knew tis not 'cause I'd eaten meat,
而是我身體入面的器官
but 'cause my internal organs
或者有些東西
or something else
開始腐爛
began to rot.
即是所謂我們的內傷
That's what we call internal injury.
那你飲天水 就可以幫你
Then Heavenly Fluid can help you
回復起身體的器官的一些內傷
heal your organ's internal injury.
那你可不可以告訴大家
Then could you tell us
你大概飲了多久 便真的有一個好明顯的
how long after drinking it
身體是出現一個好轉
did your health show an obvious improvement?
其實最明顯、最快的就是
Indeed, the most obvious and fastest way
搽頭髮
is to apply heavenly fluid
用天水搽頭髮
to your hair.
可能兩個禮拜已經看到
It may take just two weeks
白髮變黑髮
to find your hair turning from white to black
又濃密了And growing thicker.
白髮變黑 不是全部
Not all your hair turning black.
你可能會發現某一撮頭髮會早一點變黑
But you'll find a pinch of it blackening 1st.
而且你掉頭髮是減少了And your hair loss
掉頭髮少了的
will be reduced.
另外呢 就是搽皮膚
Next is application to the skin.
其實皮膚呢
When you apply heavenly fluid to the skin,
你搽皮膚 皮膚也能吸收天水
it can be absorbed by the skin.
因為它本身會吸收水份
As the skin itself can absorb moisture,
所以天水也會從你的皮膚入血
urine can enter your blood via your skin.
甚至乎我研究到有些做法
I've even found another way:-
是直接用針把天水打入皮膚
i.e. to directly inject heavenly fluid
即是用注射式
into the skin with a needle.
是的 Osiris 也有用 因為好多年前
Yes, Western medicine also uses it. Years ago,
我看過一個影片 就是講有一個心臟藥
I saw a video about a heart disease drug
是特效心臟藥來的 他們是用呢個尿酶素
which uses urea.
他就賣到很貴 即使去到大陸
Its price's very high;
那些藥廠製藥 講的差唔多…  （（恕難明白））
Even when tis manufactured in China,
十幾年前說的都好像是接近一萬元美金 是啊
it cost almost US$10K 10 odd yrs. ago!
那麼那些尿酶素是如何做呢
How's the urea produced?
他們是收集了大量的尿液
A lot of urine was collected.
然後不知多少桶呢
It took numerous barrels of urine
才做到一粒尿酶素藥丸
to prepare 1 urea pill.
那其實是對某種心臟病的特效藥劑 是呀
Tis a wonder drug for heart disease. Yes!
聽眾都可能會有好多疑問
Many watchers may have many queries.
就是會覺得
They may be concerned:
就算我想試用天水
I may wanna try heavenly fluid,
又或者我衝破了心理障礙啦
or I've overcome the psychological barrier.
很多人還是會關心「啊! 我本身身體都有病喎!」
But still many people're worried, "But I'm ill!"
因為通常也是因為現在身體有事
For usu. you won't be willing to try it
你才會勇於去嘗試這個方式啦
unless you got a health problem.
那他們還應不應飲用天水呢
They wonder if they should drink urine while sick,
又或者飲用天水 有沒有一些避忌
Or are there any don'ts about urine drinking?
可能是有甚麼病不能飲呢
Or is it bad for certain diseases?
或者有沒有甚麼特別的徵狀 飲天水會特別好
Or is it esp. good for certain symptoms?
即如嘉賓 Victor 那樣
Just like our guest Victor.
他當時就是去到身體應該是糖尿二期
He was then at Diabetes Stage II
又有爛腳的樣子啦
with Athlete's Foot.
你那個時候
At that time,
是如何用天水
how did you use heavenly fluid?
或者你開頭你都在說
As put by yourself,
你的天水的質素都不是那麼好呀
your urine's quality then was no good.
是如何慢慢從飲用天水
How did you gradually drink urine
改善到個身體之後
till your health improved
就令到自己之後的天水And your heavenly fluid
也越來越好
kept improving, too?
剛巧我看到 其實很多關於「三焦」的情況
I've read a lot about the "three burners",
就有一個叫「焦消症」的
including "burner diabetes"
他們也是用天水作治理
which can be cured by uropathy.
可否簡短的說一下 甚麼叫做「三焦」
Pls briefly explain what's "three burners"
可能中醫常說的「三焦」
What's "three burners"
甚麼謂之「三焦」呢
in Chinese herbal medicine?
「中焦」就是你的肝、膽、胰臟
The "middle burner" comprises your liver, gall bladder, spleen.
那個部位開始腐爛
The part which begins to rot,
即是開始發炎 開始去到變壞那個程度
i.e. to become inflamed, is usu. in the middle burner,
通常是在中焦的 因為現代人大多是富貴病嘛
as most modern people got Rich Man's Disease.
那麼然後呢
And then?
就去到「下焦」呢
Then comes the "lower burner"
腳趾距離你的心臟是最遠的
Toes're farthest away from your heart.
那麼「下焦」那個情況呢
What about the "lower burner"?
就是說你的腳趾離開你的身體最遠
As your toes're farthest away from your trunk,
所以所有的血氣
in terms of sap,
它是最弱的
they're the weakest.
如是者在你腳趾腐爛的那個情況呢
When your toes rot,
它的復原呢
how do they recover?
有些情況是
In some situations,
你剪腳甲
when you trim 1 of your toes' nails,
然後就流血不止
it may bleed without end.
然後你去看西醫
When you consult a Western-style doctor,
他就叫你截掉它！
he'll ask you to amputate it!
所以在這個情況 我就看到好多
I've seen many such cases.
更加會令到我願意嘗試這個天水啦
Makes me wanna try uropathy ever more.
而亦都相對來說 我飲了天水之後
After drinking heavenly fluid
應該兩個禮拜左右 我已經感覺到個傷口
for about 2 wks, I already felt my wound
已經在入面已經有好轉呀 不是從外面啊
healing from within rather than without.
即是你身體機能開始慢慢回復過來
So your body began to gradually recover.
你看到傷口內裏已經有變化
The wound's visibly changing inside.
然後我再拿些天水灑上去
Then I sprayed some urine onto my wound
或者說我有時拿來…浸浸它 And sometimes soaked my wound in urine.
拿個水盤放水 將天水加熱
I'd warm up urine in a basin with water
浸泡一下傷口呢And soak my wound in it.
那麼傷口是復元得好快
My wound then healed real quick.
與及我身體入面那些所謂無名瘡腫And the nameless swellings in my body
亦都散走了
were all gone.
是呀 那麼這個更加給了我信心
Yes, this gave me confidence
去知道這個是良好反應
that tis a good reaction.
那麼自己如何克服初期
How did I overcome the initial
那個天水的質素呢
quality of the heavenly fluid?
話說它的氣味色素都好差
Both its odor and color were very poor.
因為我查過
I've found that
天水的氣味差呢
when your urine smells awful,
就是身體的內臟開始變差
it means your viscera're worsening.
但我亦查到一件事
But I've also found that
就是你身體那自我療癒系統
your self-healing system
或者是你的免疫系統 是不斷在運作
or your immunity system is constantly working.
只是問題在於 它是十個茶壺九個蓋
The question is whether its efficiency
七個蓋、五個蓋那樣子
is 90% or 70% or 50%.
它還是一直在工作啊
Anyway, tis always working.
那麼你身體自己 它用回自己基本有的東西
Even if you feed your body
你每日給它的垃圾也好 不健康的東西也好With garbage, it can still regulate
他還是可以去調節回你的身體那個情況
your health with its basics.
只是問題在於 你食藥
The problem is that when you take medication,
它不會追蹤你的病況
it won't track your illness's state
像飛彈般瞄準你的病灶的嘛And aim at your lesion like a missile.
藥物只能集中某一方面
Medication can only focus on one aspect
例如提供功能 讓你不要發炎呀
like stopping your inflammation,
或者改變你某些狀況
or changing certain conditions of yours,
是這樣而已
nothing more.
所以論覆蓋面呢
Urine covers
天水的覆蓋面是大好多
much more,
他因為它是在你身體出來的
for it comes from your body.
他是剛剛幫你調整完你的身體療癒
It helps to adjust and heal your body,
那個修復了的新陳代謝之後的
restoring your metabolism.
即所謂你的血清素
Your serum,
經過你的心、腎臟Through your kidneys,
再滴漏到你的膀胱
dribbles to your bladder.
即是說 在你膀胱入面那些東西
i.e. what's in your bladder
完完全全是你身體的情況
represents your body's condition,
好多訊息在裏面
with lot of messages inside.
我自己會去想
I wonder
雖然很難說 到底為甚麼會有一個科學的根據
how scientifically
是醫好你啦
it cures you.
可能用一個「順勢療法」的思維
We may adopt a homeopathic way of thinking.
那就是你飲用當刻
When you drink your urine
你自己身體分泌出來的訊息
as information secreted by your body,
因為你自己身體的信息裏面 帶有一些不好的訊息
the latter may carry certain bad messages,
通常也是你自己不好的身體狀況啦
usu. about your poor bodily condition,
或者是一些病痛那樣子
or your ailments.
然後你飲回帶有這些訊息的東西
When you drink back these messages,
就他重啓回去
it will reboot
讓你好似順勢療法那樣 你是讓自己身體And rearm your body with an adaptive power
得回一個適應能力啦
just like homeopathy;
或者是去推動力的身體去對抗那個病患
or it'll drive your body to fight the disease
或者去調節你的身體
or it'll adjust your body
回到一個平衡的狀態那樣And return it to a balanced state.
所以就是說 飲用的時候呢
In urine drinking,
也是飲用自己的天水啦
we usu. drink our own urine.
那當然啦 我猜好多人都…
Of course, I guess many people find it
你自己都未接受到 更加接受不到飲別人的啦
hard to accept one's own urine, let alone others'.
其實就不是飲別人的天水
Should we drink the urine
即不是去飲一些所謂別人屙出來那些
discharged by someone else
質素更好啊 是否應該飲別人那些呢 不是的
if its quality is better?
其實應該是 愈衝破到自己的心理障礙
When we can break through the psychological barrier,
與及一是帶有自己身體的訊息呢
we should drink only our own urine
更加應該只飲自己的天水
as it contains our body's messages.
是否這樣去解釋
Don't you think so?
我開首都說過
I've already said
一百個人飲用天水 有一百個人的方式
different people drink urine in different ways.
那你說可不可以飲用其他人的天水呢
Can we drink others' urine?
是可以的
Yes.
只不過你在甚麼條件下去飲呢
But under what conditions?
那麼我在這裏又講不到太多
I can't talk too much here.
若以中醫來計 他就用了童子尿做藥引啦
Children's urine is used as a conductor in Chinese medicine.
童子尿就有它的一些很…
For children's urine
因為小朋友 他有許多好東西在天水裏
is very rich
是好豐富的嘛
in a lot of good substances.
那麼
About this respect,
這方面我暫時不想講太多
I don't wanna talk too much.
是可以飲用其他人的天水
Yes, you may drink others' urine.
甚至兩夫妻
To solve a certain problem,
因為某個問題 你亦都可以飲用對方的天水
husband and wife may exchange urine to drink,
而大家去做一個修正差別
thereby rectifying the differnce
而去達到某個目的 這裏我不多談了
to achieve a certain purpose.
好啦 然後說你身體
OK,
那些在你膀胱滴漏下來之後
primarily you have to drink
你首先是要飲用回自己的天水
your own urine dribbled from your bladder.
那你如何將那個天水去飲用呢
How do you drink it?
那麼這個經歷 就要看你自己的經歷
That depends on your own experience.
我的經歷也只屬於我自己的 我是如此這般
My experience belongs to me only.
我也是像是在街邊行過一間涼茶舖
Initially, tis as if I walked past a herbal tea shop
叫一杯苦茶And ordered a bowl of bitter herbal tea;
捏住鼻子飲了下去就算了 初初我也是這樣而已
I just pinched my nose and gulped it.
然後我曬開太陽 做很多事情配合
Then I sunbathe and do many complementary things.
但當你飲到有三、四個月之後
After drinking it for 3-4 months,
你也做洗腸呀、油拔呀And doing colonic irrigation,
背後有好多功法啦
oil pulling,
譬如綁腳
having your feet bound
綁着雙腳睡覺那些事情
during sleep, etc.
是可以將原先一杯像咖啡般黑的天水
your initially coffee-black urine
變成好似一杯香片茶般清澈的天水
will become as clear as Jasmine-tea,
即是黑茶變白茶
i.e. from black tea to white tea.
這就是你的身體那個訊息的修正
This indicates rectification of your bodily message.
所以說
Then,
是否一定要選擇這個方式呢
is it a must to choose this way?
嗱! 其實我並我不是甚麼大師、醫師
Look, I'm no master nor doctor.
但對於自然療法
But just compare natural therapy
與及現今坊間的方式
with the mainstream therapies,
那麼你是打針食藥
like injection and medication,
看醫生、施手術
consulting Western doctors and operation,
去住一間豪華的醫院
staying in a luxury hospital,
然後就
after which
臨到大去之時 也是在醫院
one passes away in a hospital.
這是現今很普遍的情況
This's very common nowadays.
那麼如果你採用自然療法
What if you adopt natural therapy,
即是說 我現在這樣子
like me now?
我就不會去醫院看病了
I won't go to the hospital for treatment.
我會用回坊間一些好簡單的自然療法
I'll use simple natural therapies
就可以了
instead.
當然了 包括你要轉變你的生活方式
Of course, you gotta change your lifestyle,
與及你要飲果菜露呀
drink smoothies,
你要洗腸呀 你要油拔呀
do colonic irrigation and oil pulling,
你要如何去將你的腰骨拉直回去
pull your backbone straight again,
是很多事宜疊加起來
etc. and etc.
加上你平時都要去一些好的環境And you gotta frequent good surroundings.
生活質素、空氣質素都要配合
Good living and air qualities are also needed.
一個整全式的醫療
A holistic treatment.
這個是自然療法的一個目標來的
That's an aim of natural therapy's.
如果你繼續是
You may continue
我是要做化療呀 我不選擇這些的
to do chemotherapy and
我繼續這些
things like that.
每一個人有每個人的選擇
Everybody makes independent choices.
所以說一百個人飲天水 有一百個人的方式
Everyone drinks urine in different ways.
至於你如何去克服障礙
As for how you may overcome the obstacles.
哇! 天水入面好多…
Oh! In urine there's a lot of...
因為我自己飲過天水
I myself have drunk urine,
我看到入面有好多一條條  的蟲And seen a lot of worms therein,
即是好像會有一些白色的東西在裏面
some white things inside.
甚至乎當我教我太太去用天水
When I first taught my wife to drink urine,
因為他那個婦女病呢
her gynecological illness
他的情況比我還要差一點
was even worse than my condition.
我後來就心想
So I thought about
如何去改善它呢 但我又要去飲
how to improve it.
我突然間又遇到一件東西
Suddenly I came across a thing.
就是有一次呢
One day,
我太太說要煮飯
my wife said she wanted to cook,
「啊! 我找不到個茶包袋喎」
but "Oh! I can't find a tea bag."
「我要將花椒八角放進去炆食物喎」
"Wanna put in pepper and anise for braising the food."
我就「叮一聲」想到啦
That really rang the bell.
那我就將我的天水做一個隔濾
I then made a filter for my urine.
我拿一個茶包袋 將它做為一個隔濾器
I used a tea bag as a filter,
雖然可能會流失了許多東西
tho' a lot of substances might be lost.
那我又是量度它的酸鹼度
I measured its alkalinity,
然後做一個隔濾
and filtered it.
然後呢 你要注意其溫度
Then you gotta take note of its temperature.
在外國生活 就可以改為用咖啡濾紙了啊 是嗎
When you live abroad, could you use coffee filter paper instead?
你就看你身邊有甚麼
It depends on what you got at hand.
我也是身邊找到甚麼 就用甚麼
I use whatever's next to me.
最近我就買了一個純棉的袋
Recently, I bought a 100% cotton bag.
那麼每一次我也是做完之後
Each time after doing urinotherapy,
我又用牙刷刷乾淨它 然後曬乾
I brush it clean with a toothbrush n dry it in the sun.
然後下次再用這樣子
Then I reuse it next time.
其實就看你身邊有甚麼可用
Depends on what you got at hand.
然後呢
And then
與及你飲的時候呢
when you drink it,
基本上有三個條件要考慮啦 第一個就是溫度
You gotta consider 3 conditions, i.e. temperature,
第二是時間 與及第三 空氣囉
time and air.
即是說
i.e.
有溫度的天水
Heavenly fluid with a warm temperature
即是有一定的狀態
has a reasonable state.
即還要一些新鮮的 還保持有體溫的天水是嗎
That's fresh urine with bodily warmth?
嗯 所以我在英國 因為天氣好冷
Yes, when I was in England, which was cold,
我就會用一個兜裝住熱水 就放我的銅杯進去
I put my copper cup in a bowl of warm water
保持住它的溫度
to hold its temperature.
即是儘管不是馬上飲
Even tho you ain't gonna drink it straight,
你都要保持住它的溫度才去飲
You gotta keep it warm.
即是不可以太過凍 是嗎 香港這個天氣就不會那麼差
It shouldn't too cold. HK's room temp.
室溫沒那麼差
is not so low.
至於計算空氣、時間
As for air and time,
你慢慢掌握囉 是嗎
You gotta grasp them slowly, right?
並不是說越快越好的
The sooner isn't the better.
而是你自己要接受它
You gotta accept it.
你望住它才飲
Look at it while drinking it.
不要閉上眼飲
Don't shut your eyes.
始終它是在幫你的
It is helping you, after all.
雖然它很乞你憎
Though it may repel you--
「好難聞喎、好大味喎」
"Oh, it stinks! It smells awful!"
但它是在幫你
But tis helping you.
看你如何克服這個關口
How're you gonna overcome this barrier?
其實放久了 經過空氣氧化
Indeed, it got odorous
才愈來愈大陣味的
only after long-time oxidation.
其實 譬如去洗手間
E.g. when we go to the toilet,
大家可能覺得氣味很餲
we may smell a putrid odor.
其實當你排出新鮮的天水來
But freshly discharged urine
我自己的天水無甚麼餲味
has almost no odor.
但當你們去完廁所 忘記沖廁呢 放久了
But when we forget to flush the toilet
會發覺它愈來愈餲
we'll find it more and more putrid.
不 那個餲味是因為人食了肉、食雜
No, that odor comes from the ammonia
而釋放的阿蒙尼亞味
released by eaten meat.
但時間耐了 氣味都會濃了
But as time goes by, the odor'll grow stronger.
我發覺是好像愈新鮮 愈沒那種餲味
The fresher, the more odorless, I've found.
我有用老齡的尿 即是放久了的尿
I also use age-old urine
即是超過三個月 或者半年的
i.e. more than 3 months/6 month old.
哦 即是你會儲起它的 對 我會儲起它
So you'll store it? Yes, I'll.
我有好多個杯
I have many cups.
其實你會發現
You'll find that
某一次的天水的狀態非常之好的話呢
when the state of a certain round's urine is very good,
他是沒甚麼氣味的
it is odorless.
即是所謂食得清 夠健康 對
Which means a healthy diet? Yes.
那個呢 初期我都有標籤日期在杯上
Initially, I put a date label on each cup.
那個就是我洗完腸之後
That one's after colonic irrigation,
再加上我是「斷食」完了
and fasting is done
是 即是我還「食生」啦 然後「斷食」啦
plus a raw food diet.
然後就保存住那一次的天水呢
The state of that time's urine
那狀態最好的 即是身體已完全排毒了
was the best. The body's wholly detoxified.
你直是不知道它有氣味的
You simply can't smell anything.
即淡到這個程度啦
Its odor is as light as that.
即是你擺在窗台上 一定有氣味
When placed on the windowsill, urine'll emit odor.
但你逐杯去聞聞它們
But when you smell them cup by cup,
跟它們聊聊天 有一些是無甚氣味的And talk to them, you'll find some of them odorless.
所以我每一次我用天水呢
So each time I use heavenly fluid,
點指兵兵那時呢 我也是要先問問它
I'll consult them,
哪些氣味大的呢 我就先用它And choose the more odorous ones.
聽起來都好有畫面感呀
Very vivid.
然後就再將它加熱
Then I warm it up,
然後再去溝開 然後拿來洗腸
dilute it and irrigate my colon with it.
即是去到很講究 洗腸都有用它 是呀
So you even use it for colonic irrigation?
這些後面再講吧
Will talk about this later.
談回你的問題 就是說你的身體不好
Back to your qt. When your health's poor,
更加需要去補充回你身體需要那個訊息
You need to replenish the message your body needs.
你可以從滴兩滴
You may start with 1 or 2 droplets
從你的舌底開始
under your tongue.
你的身體已經會知悉
Your body'll already be aware.
是呀
Yes
滴兩滴都夠的了
1 or 2 drops is enough.
取了信息先 與及飲的份量呢
Get the message 1st. Regarding the amount,
並非飲得愈多愈好的啊
"The more you drink, the better" isn't true.
因為你飲得多呢
For when you drink much,
你的身體的負荷就大了
your body'll be overloaded,
那麼你個人就變得好疲累And you'll become very tired
好想睡覺
and sleepy.
所以呢
So
你是飲一個茶杯的份量
just drink a teacup of it,
約莫是 180ml 左右
around 180 ml
180毫升 是的
yes, 180 millimeter.
那麼 你飲如此的份量
You drink this dose.
已不少的啊
Tis already something,
已經是我們那些 375 毫升盒裝飲品的一半
already half of a 373 ml juicebox.
是啦 差唔多啦 如果講份量
Yes, more or less.
就像茶餐廳那種杯的半杯茶左右
Around half a HK café teacup.
我現在飲得少一點
Now I drink less than before.
我是用一個茶杯這樣 約莫140ml左右吧
1 teacup each time, around 140 ml.
但我每天是不止飲一次的
But I drink more than once everyday.
早晚 還是早午晚這樣?
Twice daily, or thrice daily?
其實只要隨你喜歡就可以
As you like it.
何解呢 因為份量越少
Why? 'cause the lesser the amount,
你身體的負荷沒那麼大
the lesser the load on your body.
因為有一個原理 叫做「以毒攻毒」
This's called "combating one toxin with another toxin".
那你飲了落去 你個身體要馬上作戰
Right after drinking it, your body gotta do battle.
將那個你自己的療癒系統
For your healing system
自我修復系統激發了嘛
or self-restoration system is triggered.
是嗎 他真的吸收了你的訊息
It really absorbs your message
然後它又分泌一些訊息
and then secretes some other message
供其它的器官做一些內分泌
for other organs as endocrine,
即是你的尿呀、關節液呀
i.e. your urine, joint fluid,
涕、唾、油、淚、脂
snot, saliva, oil, tears, fat,
汗、血、膿、痰、膽汁
Sweat, blood, pus, phlegm, bile,
以至你的小腦
to your cerebellum.
這是你的上水道的一般器官那個訊息場
These comprise the info. field of your upper waterway organs.
那你就不怕分開多幾次飲用
You may divide it into a few times more.
反而你會輕鬆好多
Then you'll be much easier.
是否你飲得多就好呢
The more you drink, the better?
等於食藥也是早晚一次啦
You usu. take medication only twice daily
或者一日三次啦
or thrice daily.
其實是讓你的負荷減輕而已
Tis to lessen your load.
「不是喎 食兩粒藥
"No, I wish to recover sooner,
我吃夠四粒啦 我想快點好喎…」
why not 4 pills instead of 2?"
那麼你的身體就累了啦
Then your body'll become tired.
OK! OK!
其實就類似這樣了
Something like that.
你這是過來人的經驗啦
You're speaking from personal experience.
大家可以視乎你們自己的身體狀況
It depends on your own bodily condition
或者你的接受能力
or your receptivity.
或者這樣說 如果最少
For beginners like us
以我們剛剛初學這樣 初階樣子
at the elementary stage,
我每日最少飲幾多次
how many times must I drink it daily,
飲幾多量 可以達致一定有效果呢And how much each time, to get the effect?
是否即是起碼都最少一次
At least once daily?
他處於甚麼狀態先?
Depends on their bodily state.
就說身體有少許毛病先啦
Let's say the body got some illness.
說真的 你身體沒毛病
Frankly, people'd not dare to try it,
大家也未必會英勇於嘗試呢件事
if their health's ok.
嗱 我不是診症呀
Look, I'm not diagnosing.
我這樣問你身體有甚麼毛病
When I ask what's wrong with your body,
只為代入我以前在哪個階段的做法而已
I'm trying to match it against my stage.
你那個階段都頗為惡劣了
That stage of yours was rather bad:-
因為去到糖尿二期、爛腳這樣子
Diabetes stage II plus athlete's foot.
其實我覺得都頗嚴重了
I deem it rather serious.
是呀 在那個階段
Yes, at that stage,
我是一日飲兩次
I drank twice daily,
那時我飲的份量較多
and the amount each time was larger.
所以我就整日都想睡覺 好攰
So I was sleepy and fatigued all day long.
OK
因為我心急醫病嘛
For I was eager to heal myself.
但到後來發現 其實不是這樣的
Later I found it doesn't work that way.
那麼你若像我現在這樣呢
Now
我是每日都飲
I drink it daily,
每日都飲
every day,
一次至兩次
once or twice,
每一次都是一個茶杯份量
1 teacup each time.
即是剛才你說的140至180毫升之間
i.e. 140-180 ml as aforesaid by you.
那麼你個人就會好舒服
Then you'll feel easy.
是呀 你不會突然之間很攰呀這樣子
Yes. You won't suddenly feel very tired.
如果你在斷食的時候呢
When you're fasting,
好奇妙的喎
curiously,
你是不需要進食的啊
You don't have to eat.
你飲了它之後
After drinking it,
你不會說「啊! 我肚餓呀!」
You won't say, "Oh, I'm hungry!"
失去了這種飢餓感
You'll lose the feeling of hunger.
然後你去做做園藝
Then you do gardening.
那一日你就不用進食的了
And you don't have to eat that day.
你沒有飢餓感
You won't feel hungry.
除非你在斷食之前
Unless, before fasting,
食得很飽
You have eaten a lot.
那麼斷食那一日 你就會很辛苦了
Then on the day of fasting, you'll have a hard time.
我在網上看
I've found online that
有個西班牙女子
there's a Spanish girl
她是用天水斷食31日
who fasted for 31 days with heavenly fluid.
她也是說「我喜歡飲就飲 隨我鍾意」
"I drink it whenever I want to," she also said.
即是她也是邊飲天水 邊做斷食 她做31天
i.e. she fasted for 31 days while drinking urine.
所以其實你問的那問題
Just now, you asked me
就是如果好似現在我同你這個狀態這樣
what to do
如果你現在這個狀態
in a state like yours and mine now.
就等如我那個時候
In those days,
我也是一日飲…
Everyday I also drank...
斷食的時候 我一日會飲三至四次
When fasting, I drank it 3 to 4 times daily.
我會袋住一個杯出街的
I'd carry a cup with me when I went out.
但如果我平時呢
In normal times,
我就一日飲兩次
I'd drink twice daily.
有時我也是一日飲一次
Sometimes, I drank once daily.
就看自己在甚麼狀態
Depends on my state.
那現在你太太也是跟你一樣
Now does your wife also drink urine
也是同樣每日最少飲一次是嗎
at least once daily like you?
另外再加上 好似用爽膚水那樣啦
In addition, she applies it as toner
搽頭髮那樣呀
to her hair.
我見你真的是…
I think you're really...
不 有些人呢
No, some people
就一定會敷在心臟處
apply it to their heart.
為甚麼是敷在心臟位置呢
Why the heart?
因為你敷在心那個位置呢
For your heart is then
你的心臟去吸收那天水是最接近的
closest to the heavenly fluid.
即是你不用口服
Then you don't have to take it orally.
直接搽落心臟
Simply apply it to your heart
讓它直接去吸收
for it to absorb directly.
因皮膚吸收
Whatever's absorbed by your skin,
是替你直接入血的嘛
goes straight into your blood.
那個距離是最近的嘛
The distance is the closest.
我還見到有些人
I've also seen someone
他是拿一塊繃紗帶
stick a piece of bandage
固定在他的背脊位置
to their backbone,
即好像跌打敷藥般
just like applying Chinese bone balm,
哦 是
Oh, yes.
然後他還用保鮮紙包住它
He then wrapped it in plastic wrap,
讓天水最直接進入那個部位
so that the urine'd go straight into the area.
這裏是有着不同的方式
There're different ways to do it.
這個明白的
I see.
大家如果有甚麼是要注意的
What else people have to pay heed to?
就是有沒有所謂的…
Is there any...
不光是說你自己親身做
Based on not only your own experience
其實你之前從網上、從書本
but on what you've learnt from books
你都看過好多嘛
and from the net,
你看過的這些資料
have you come across any information
其實有沒有說某些人
about what kind of people
或者甚麼狀態下的人
or what kind of state of people
是不適合天水療法的呢
is not suitable for urinotherapy?
又或者有沒有哪些症狀是特別有效?
Or is it esp. good for any symptoms?
起碼即是你自己這個糖尿二期
At least for your diabetes stage II
是特別有效啦
it's particularly effective.
你有個朋友就直接拿來搽身喇
A friend of yours applied it to his body straight
將自己那個濕疹 直是換了皮膚般樣子啦
and replaced her eczema with smooth skin.
對啦 除了這個糖尿病和濕疹之外
Apart from diabetes and eczema,
那是至少你有自己的親身經驗
which based on your experience,
與朋友的經驗特別好之外
and your friend's experience, uropathy serves well,
有沒有甚麼情況 是特別適合 或特別不適合使用天水
are there any conditions esp. suitable
可以提一提點大家的呢
or esp. unsuitable for uropathy?
你用天水
Is heavenly fluid
是否一定是飲用為最好呢
best for drinking?
其實要看你自己感到舒服
It depends on whether you feel comfortable.
那麼你如果連外敷都接受不了
If you can't even accept external application,
那麼你就無謂去飲啦 免得你不舒服
then don't drink it,
令那個「好轉反應」更大
lest that the healing crisis is too much.
其實我們當初都說過
We've mentioned
當初為甚麼會接觸尿療法
why I approached urinotherapy in the 1st place.
為甚麼你會搞這套 也是看到一些紀錄片在談論它
Tis 'cause I saw some documentaries on it.
其實都是對上一些有病痛的人
Usu. only people with ailments
他們會去嘗試 或者真的無辦法了
would try it; they can't but
他都要衝破這個心理關口
break through the psychological barrier
他也要「不妨試一試啦」這樣子
and "give it a try".
是呀 我的朋友 我通常不跟他說
Yes. I usu. don't tell my friends
我有飲用天水呀 我都只是囑咐朋友
I'm drinking urine. I just advise them
「你做做油拔吧」「洗洗腸吧」
to do oil pulling, colonic irrigation,
「拌些果菜露飲吧」這樣
and to drink smoothie.
如果他連這些事情都不做
If they won't even do these,
那麼我跟他講再多的都沒用 是嗎
tis useless to tell them more, right?
這些都不去嘗試
When they wouldn't even try these,
很難一下子就用天水那麼極端
tis hard for them to go as far as uropathy.
有些朋友 他連飲「水克菲爾」都接受不了的
Some friends can't even accept kefir,
那你就無謂跟他談天水方面的事情啦
why tell them about heavenly fluid?
這是他個人的抉擇囉
That's their personal choice.
那麼我相信…
Then I believe...
甚麼人不適宜飲天水呢
What kind of people isn't suitable for uropathy?
如果你接受不了 你就無需要飲了
If you can't accept it, then don't drink it.
若以我自己作計算
In my case,
我太太也是
my wife initially
一開始都沒有陪我一齊飲
did not drink it with me either.
但我做這件事 我是有跟她分享的
But I did tell her about my practice.
原因是我看了很多英文平台的資訊
I've read a lot of info. on English platforms.
因為英文程度不太好
As my English is no good,
有好多資料 是我太太替我翻譯的
my wife's translated a lot of info. for me.
看完之後…雖然Google有translate功能
Though there's google-translate,
但有些語法譯出來不暢順
the translation is often not so fluent.
Penny 替我看過後
After going through it for me, and Penny
還是未開始用天水的啊
still didn't start drinking urine.
是我開始先的
I started first.
而我開始了差不多一年多
Tis not until I'd done it for over 1 yr.,
她才開始的啊
that she started.
最初她同樣是接受不了的
Initially she couldn't accept it either.
嗯 反而這方面你可問問她啦
You may ask her about this.
為甚麼她會開始呢
Why did she ever begin?
這亦是因為她身體有問題
Tis also because she's ill.
那麼如果你除了聽完這一集節目之外
Apart from this episode,
可能有些人仍然希望挖掘多點天水資料
pls recommend more sources on uropathy,
那麼有沒有一些的書籍 或者你聽過的
be it books or what you've heard,
可以介紹給大家的呢 無論中英文都可以
both Eng. and Chin. will do.
譬如我知道中文方面
E.g. concerning Chin. sources,
就有一本叫做《尿療法治百病》的書
there's a book entitled Urinotherapy Cures Every Disease;
有一本就叫《回龍湯》啦
Another one is The Returning Dragon's Soup.
談去這裏 我就找來 Victor 和 Penny
We're honored to have Victor and Penny.
她就看了一些外國書籍
She's read some foreign books
再吸收了多些關於天水療法的知識
on urinotherapy.
那其實有沒有一些書籍
Would you pls recommend some books
介紹給大家
to our audience?
如果可以的話 我就放一些連結在這裏
If possible, I'll put some links here
讓大家有興趣可以找到一些相關的中英文書籍
to related English and Chinese books
去再學多一些
for your reference.
看那些英文書籍
Would you pls recommend
其實有沒有哪一兩本特別出名的著作
one or two well known Eng. books
給大家試讀
on urinotherapy?
有一本書叫做 "The water of life"
There's a book called The Water of Life.
另外一些你就要搜尋關於 "Aging Urine" 的
You may search for Aging Urine as well.
因為他們說那些「舊天水」是很好的
They say "aging urine" is very good.
那我要的真找找這兩本書的連結
I will find the links to these 2 books,
我就放在今集下邊位置啦
and put them below this episode
大家可以去看看
for your reference.
用這些字眼去搜尋 找着找着
Search for these key words
應該找到很多相關的資料 是啊And you'll find a lot of related info. Yes.
通常大部分的書籍 網上資料都在說
Most books and online materials advise you
飲用朝早起身第一篤天水啦
to drink the 1st round of urine every morning.
關於飲用的時間與及
As for the drinking schedule,
飲用的杯子的物料 有沒有甚麼講究
and the material of the cup,
你可以跟大家分享一下嗎
do you have any specifications?
我看過一個影片
I have seen a video
是台灣一對夫婦劉先生
about a Taiwanese Mr. Lau and his wife
他在影片中就有講述到
In that video he mentions
他不用玻璃杯飲天水
that he doesn't drink urine with a glass
他說原因是
He says tis because
他就是說現今的玻璃已經纖維化了
Today's glass is in fact fibreglass,
加了很多纖維進去
reinforced with a lot of fibre.
杯子做得很快 做得很薄
This kind of quickly made glasses is very thin;
於是乎 因為天水中有阿蒙尼亞那些東西
as urine contains Ammonia,
於是你的天水的質素
the quality of your urine
就會打折扣
will be compromised.
有些揮發了 你可能只剩下……
Some of it will volatize...
我又不想說剩下多少
I don't wanna say how much'll be left.
所以如果你知道會流失
When you know the loss's preventable,
可以避免的話 那你就去避免 是嗎
surely you'll try to prevent it, right?
因為如果你上網看 很多人甚至用紅酒杯飲
Many people even drink it with red wine cups.
但如果你看完這條影片之後呢
But after I watched that video...
其實影片在說
In fact it's talking about...
我就找到有一篇文章談到
I've found an article which says
他是用「金、銀、銅」物料
"Gold, silver and copper" are used as materials.
排位?
How about the order of importance?
金杯、銀杯、銅杯
Gold cup, silver cup, copper cup.
是的 或者竹造的杯
Yes. Or bamboo cup;
甚至乎用樹葉都可以的
Even leaf may be used.
是的 用樹葉 那你剪一張樹葉
Yes, you may cut a leaf
那些芭蕉葉又好 裹糉葉也好
be it banana leaf or lotus leaf
剪成銀紙般大小
Size it down into the size of a banknote
放在銀包裏
Put it in your wallet.
那麼當你到了要飲的時候
When you need to drink urine,
你就去洗手間 將它捲一捲
go to the washroom,
就褶成一個杯囉 有這個做法
and fold it into a cup.
OK 我這裏跟你說
Look
其實杯子沒特別講究一定要哪隻杯才最好
You don't have to be particular about
是否一定要某隻杯才可以
what kind of cup to use.
總之起碼大家可以
But at least
盡量不用玻璃杯
try not to use a glass cup.
因為現代的玻璃未必好
For modern glass isn't necessarily good.
即是杯子其實不是很講究 即如剛才說
Again, you don't have to be particular about the cup.
甚至用樹葉都可以啦
Even a leaf will do.
那時間上呢
How about the timing?
是否飲用朝早第一篤真的最好?
Is the first round of urine in the morning the best?
杯子方面 我是這樣的
Concerning cup, I use
有用銅杯和銀杯 飲下去那個感覺是不同的
both copper and silver cups.
你會覺得高貴好多
Will make you feel much more high-class
高格調好多
or elitist.
我都覺得如此 金杯應該高貴一些
Yes, a gold cup should feel more high-class.
如果四條九足金就更如是啦 當然最好啦
A 9999 gold cup is surely the best.
至於你問到幾時飲呢
As for the time for drinking,
其實一般來說是朝早啦 是嗎
tis usu. early in the morning, isn't it?
我亦都有考究過
I've done some research,
查過一些影片
and gone through some videos,
說過在半夜…
which say midnight...
半夜起床?!
What? Get up at midnight?!
半夜兩點半至四點半那個時候
Between 2:30 am and 4:30 am.
那麼各位如果有去屙夜尿的朋友
Those of you who oft wake up at night to pee
就有福啦
are blessed.
不是 其實不用刻意起床
No, you don't have to painstakingly
飲這個天水
get up at nite to drink urine.
那個講法呢
The argument
就是說
is as follows:
當你一個人
When you
處於一個休息狀態
are in a resting mode,
休眠狀態
a dormant mode,
乃至於睡眠狀態
a slumber state,
即是你個人靜止了
i.e. when you are at rest
你在一個全黑的地方
in a completely dark place,
那麼你的身體
your body will
就會分泌一個褪黑色素
secret melatonin,
即是由你的腎上腺
i.e. your adrenal glands
分泌一些褪黑色素去保護你
will secrete melatonin to protect you.
但這個褪黑色素
But this melatonin secretion
它不會維持整晚 可能維持兩個小時左右
will only last around 2 hours at night.
因為當你去到一個睡眠狀態之後
After you reach a certain state of sleep,
那個褪黑色素就消退了
the melatonin will fade away.
他說的這個原理就是
The theory is:-
古人以前去打獵
When ancient guys went hunting,
害怕有些老虎叼走你
they were afraid they'd be eaten up by tigers.
所以他就會處於緊張的防備狀態中睡覺
So they slept in a state of alert,
那麼他的身體就會有這個褪黑色素出來
and their body'd secrete melatonin.
關於這個黑色素
About this melatonin,
我最近聽朋友講
I've heard that
更有用它製成的藥丸出售
there're pills made of it for sale.
但我相信你飲回你自己那些天水是最好的
But I think tis best to drink your own urine.
於是乎在這個基礎下
In this context,
就有些人講
some people say
飲兩三點鐘的天水最佳
urine discharged between 2 and 3 am is the best,
因為含有那種激素
as it contains melatonin.
但至於你說 要不要調校鬧鐘起來飲
But I don't think you have to
那我就認為不需要
set an alarm to drink it.
如果你真的要在這個時間飲天水呢
If you really wanna drink urine at this hour,
那麼你應該早點睡覺
then you should go to bed early,
早些睡覺啦 你的身體在一個好狀態
and your body'll be in a good state.
早睡怎麼樣總是好的
Tis good to sleep early anyway.
與及不要吃太多碳水化合物
And don't eat too much carbohydrate.
因為碳水化合物會令你很累
For it'll make you very tired,
會令你的黑色素分泌時間縮短
and shorten your duration of melatonin secretion.
哦 明白
Got it.
這個是 我只說這是我習慣如此而已
This is just my own habit.
但我現在現在都沒有特意起床
But I do not get up specifically
去飲天水呀
to drink heavenly fluid.
跟住當天的感覺 順其自然
I follow the day's feel. You let nature take its course.
即是去到兩三點 夢夢鬆鬆
i.e. between 2 and 3 am, in a dreaming state,
記得就飲 忘記了就算啦 這樣
drink it if you remember, otherwise let it be.
與及他說 你一定要把燈全關掉
And they say you gotta turn off all the lights.
在個漆黑漆的地方睡覺 你的黑色素才會出來
Only when you sleep in a pitch-dark place will your melatonin come out.
如果你着了燈睡覺
When you sleep with the lights on,
即是你自己尚未進入那個防備狀態
and you're still in the mode of alert,
那個黑色素是不會分泌出來的
melatonin won't be secreted.
哦 明白
I see.
好了 兩集的時間就來到這裏了
OK, these 2 episodes are coming to an end.
我猜大家會自己做做功課
I guess you'll do your homework
決定要不要嘗試
and decide whether to try it.
又或者 到底你會不會
Or, will you try it
在身體無甚病痛下都去嘗試呢
even if your health is alright?
還是像 Victor 般屬於比較「異類」的人
Or are you somewhat "extraordinary" like Victor?
或真的可能身體有些病痛了
Maybe when you're really ill,
及至真有點兒無法處理的時候
and unable to cope with it,
終於去勇於嘗試
You'll finally have the courage to try it.
另外有一件頗吸引我的事
There's an anecdote rather intriguing for me.
就是我見到中醫書籍裏有個故事
Acc. to a Chinese herbal medicine book,
一篇古文記載了一位醫師
a doctor in ancient times
他見到一位老婦
came across an old woman.
應該說他見到一個年約八十歲婦人
She's aged 80,
但樣子看上去卻只四十歲左右
but she looked like 40.
然後醫師就問這個婦人原因
The doctor asked her how come.
婦人說 她以前身體有病
She said she had been sick.
聞說飲這個天水可以醫病
Ever since she heard drinking urine can cure illnesses,
她就是由那個時候飲到現在
she'd been drinking it.
所以就說這個中醫寫這個故事
The doctor put down this story,
記載了有人樣子相當年輕
recording that someone who regularly drank urine
而這個人是有長年飲用天水 因而有這個效用
looked rather young.
雖然沒講到是否直接有關
Tis not stated whether tis causation
這個無法考究
or correlation.
但幾本中醫書都有說過
But tis mentioned in several Chinese medicine books.
其中談到飲用這個天水
It is said that drinking urine
可能有這個回春 又或者凍齡的效果
may rejuvenate people or keep them young.
我相信很多女士們
I believe many ladies
這方面可能比男士更加勇敢了
are braver than men in this aspect.
應該你無病無痛的時候
Even if you aren't ill,
都不妨試下 而跟Victor都談到
You may give it a try. Victor's also talked about
如果你剛好真的有勇氣嘗試的時候
how to break through the psychological barrier
你如何衝破心理關口
if you're courageous enough to try it.
先不用飲的啦 先來外敷啦
Initially, instead of drinking it,
你用作外敷 搽皮膚呀 用過搽頭髮呀
You may try external application to skin or hair.
你見到有效果 有改善
When you see some effect or improvement,
那你自然就有更大的信心
You'll have more confidence
考慮是否真的去到飲用狀態啦
to consider whether to drink it.
其他事情呢 剛才這兩集都講過
As mentioned in these 2 episodes,
一百個人心態 有一百個人不同的方法和效果
different people have different ways and effects.
因為這一門療法 沒有一個尿療法醫師
Regarding this therapy, there's no
或療法的大師呀 沒有這人物存在
great master.
那就靠大家自己聽完這兩集節目
After seeing these 2 episodes,
再多做功課
You're supposed to do your homework
你自己決定如何嘗試 如何做啦
and decide how to do it.
我們訪問Victor
We interview Victor
以他作為一個真的用了超過三年以上經驗的人
simply because he has done it for over 3 years
去做一個分享而已
and he's willing to share his experience.
臨尾Victor 是否還有一些東西想分享下
Victor, do you still have something else to share?
其實我們飲用天水
Drinking urine
這是一個大自然的現象
is a natural phenomenon.
一棵樹
A tree
它去到秋天
in Autumn
它要過冬 要落葉
will shed leaves,
葉是落在它的根部
which will fall on its roots,
它的根部就是吸收回那些樹葉
and its roots will absorb back those leaves,
來準備給自己過冬
for itself to survive Winter.
而這個所謂回春的方法
This method of rejuvenation
你也是一樣
is also
這是個大自然現象
a phenomenon of nature.
大家如何去用
How to use it?
其實由外敷開始 你見到那個效果最明顯了
Start with ext. application whose effect's apparent.
「啊! 我心不舒服…」你可以搽心口
When your heart aches, apply urine to it.
我都是這樣 哪裏不舒服 我就敷哪裏
I myself apply it to whichever part feels uneasy.
你可以保存一些
You may store some heavenly fluid
你用一個瓷器保存住一些天水
in a porcelain container
你擺放一段時間
for some time.
你越放得耐
The longer the storing time,
用那天水來搽皮膚傷患
the more effective it is,
效果愈見快速
when tis applied to skin troubles.
你不用理會天水的質素好不好
You don't have to care about its quality.
你沒量度酸鹼度又好 它很大氣味又好
Even if its odor is strong and its alkalinity unchecked,
無論如何 你都拿來搽你的傷口
You may apply it to your wound.
例如被蛇咬啊
E.g. when you're bitten by a snake.
怎麼樣都好 這是一些古典書籍都有記載的
This is recorded in ancient books.
或蚊釘蟲咬等 對
Yes, mosquito-sting or bug-bite.
你可以用一個很細的小花樽裝起來
You may store it in a very small vase.
但小花樽的樽口偏細 你或可用一隻杯裝起它
But its mouth may be too small. Ok, store it in a cup
然後用一條毛巾蓋住它 再用橡皮圈紮住它
Cover it with a cloth and bound it with a rubber band,
即是好像製水克菲爾那樣
the way Kefir is made,
讓它進行一個鍊金術效果
and let it go through an alchemical process,
讓它曬曬太陽 曬曬月光
Expose it to sunshine and moonlight,
然後你拿來搽
and then apply it to your skin.
是一個好神奇 好奇妙的治療方式
Tis a very marvelous therapy.
尤其是燒傷、燙傷
Esp. for burns and scalds,
效果非常快
the effect is real quick.
好
Fine.
好了 真的終於今集要完結了
Fine, this episode's really gonna end.
希望這兩集幫到有需要的朋友啦
Hope these 2 episodes are of use to friends in need.
你就即管先聽聽內容
Listen to the contents first.
不知道這一集到底可以幫到幾多人
Wonder how many people this episode can help,
或者有幾多人真的肯嘗試喇
or how many people are willing to try.
如果你曾經試過
If you've tried it,
又或者試過之後有甚麼效果 你不妨到時…
you may contact us in private
很好的或很差的 你都可以私下找我And discuss the effect with us,
跟我們談談它
be it good or bad.
好啦 今日今集時間就這麼多了
OK, this episode will end here.
多謝 Victor 啦
Thank you Victor.
多謝大家 多謝大家
Thank you everybody.
那麼好啦
Fine.
拜拜 拜拜
Byebye. Byebye.